<?xml version="1.0"?>
<document>
	<properties>
		<title>JCR-Explorer</title>
	</properties>
	<body>
		<div id="downloadbox">
			<h3>Get JCR-Explorer</h3>
			<p>
				<a href="downloads.html">JCR-Explorer 0.9.5 Binary</a>
				<small>(4.6Mb)</small>
				<span style="font-size: smaller">
					Released: 9 August 2007
				</span>
			</p>
		</div>
		<section
			name="JCR-Explorer - A web-based explorer tool for JSR-170, JCR, Jackrabbit...">
			<p>
				This web-based tool is based on plain JSF. It aims to
				provide support for all features of JCR-Repository
				including optional features like versioning.
			</p>
			<p>
				The specification for JCR 1.0 can be found
				<a href="http://jcp.org/en/jsr/detail?id=170"
					class="externalLink"
					title="JSR 170: Content Repository for Java(TM) technology API">
					here
				</a>
				, the work in progress for 2.0 can be found here:
				<a href="http://jcp.org/en/jsr/detail?id=283"
					class="externalLink"
					title="JSR 283: Content Repository for JavaTM Technology API Version 2.0">
					here
				</a>
				.
			</p>
			<p>
				For development the implementation Apache Jackrabbit is
				used, which can be found here:
				<a href="http://jackrabbit.apache.org"
					class="externalLink" title="Apache Jackrabbit">
					here
				</a>
				.
			</p>
		</section>
		<subsection name="Project status and downloads">
			<p>
				The project is still under early development, but
				browsing and editing of most property types should work
				by now, also some more features like querying or
				import/export are implemented. Furthermore the GUI is
				still an issue, it's not Any comments, feedback or
				contribution is highly appreciated. The Explorer is
				still in a stage of early development but it gets some
				kind of stable by now. Main features including the ones
				of the current snapshot version are:
				<ul>
					<li>Browsing repository content</li>
					<li>Editing all kinds of properties</li>
					<li>
						Standard operations on nodes like adding and
						removing nodes, properties and mixin node types,
						locking, check-in/check-out
					</li>
					<li>Showing versions of versionable nodes</li>
					<li>Showing lock details of locked nodes</li>
					<li>
						Showing information of the current Repository,
						Session and Workspace (like vendor informations,
						repository descriptors, ...)
					</li>
					<li>Queries using available query languages</li>
				</ul>
			</p>
			<p>
				The current stable release is 0.9.5. As the project is
				under development, new features and bugfixes can be
				checked out by getting the latest sources from SVN. You
				can also check out the progress the following:
			</p>
			<ul>
				<li>
					<a
						href="http://sourceforge.net/tracker/?group_id=193255"
						class="externalLink" title="Tracker on SourceForge">
						Tracker Summary on SourceForge
					</a>
					(you can filter by versions, for example)
				</li>
				<li>
					<a
						href="http://jcr-webexplorer.svn.sourceforge.net/viewvc/jcr-webexplorer/explorer/trunk/CHANGELOG.txt?view=markup"
						class="externalLink" title="CHANGELOG.txt via ViewVC">
						CHANGELOG.txt
					</a>
					located in the root of the project in Subversion
					(via SVN WebAccess)
				</li>
			</ul>
		</subsection>
		<subsection name="JCR-Explorer News">
			<dl>
				<dt>
					<strong>
						Oktober 12, 2007: JBoss RichFaces used in new
						version
					</strong>
				</dt>
				<dd>
					During the last weeks, a couple of JSF-related
					frameworks and component libraries have been
					evaluated in order to find the future directon for
					the Explorer. Dropping JSF in general has never been
					an option, but a little bit more Web 2.0 would be
					nice. However, finally JBoss RichFaces became the
					component library of choice which is intended to
					solve some issues. First of all, the navigation
					should be changed to a nice Explorer-like tree view.
					Furthermore, the GUI should get a facelift and
					become a little bit more robust. Not really
					required, but definitely nice to have and useful is
					the built-in AJAX support that comes with RichFaces.
					So far, the integration runs pretty smoothly so that
					the release of RichFaces-powered JCR-Explorer 0.9.6
					can hopefully roll out soon.
				</dd>
			</dl>
			<dl>
				<dt>
					<strong>
						August 09, 2007: Version 0.9.5 released, binary
						download available now
					</strong>
				</dt>
				<dd>
					The binary download for the new version 0.9.5 is now
					available on SourceForge.
				</dd>
			</dl>
			<dl>
				<dt>
					<strong>
						July 22, 2007: Binary download available for
						version 0.9.4b
					</strong>
				</dt>
				<dd>
					Due to a couple of user requests a binary version of
					the latest stable release 0.9.4b is now available.
					The release mainly contains a WAR archive that just
					should be deployed into your web container. Now
					available on the download page.
				</dd>
			</dl>
		</subsection>

	</body>
</document>
